changemakers.net 2012-06-12

# Privacy Policy | Changemakers

## **Changemakers Privacy Policy**

### Introduction

The privacy of your personal information is important to Ashoka (“Changemakers” or “we”). This privacy policy (this “Privacy Policy”) is provided to explain our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way that your personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) is collected and used at the Changemakers website and all other websites owned or controlled by Changemakers (collectively, the “Site”).  
If you are an employee of Changemakers or its affiliates, please note that other internal company policies apply to you related to employee use of company computer systems and networks.  
Please note that by using the Site, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is effective as of March 23, 2010.

### Passive Information Collection; Cookies

A cookie is a text-only piece of information that a website transfers to your computer’s hard disk so that the website can remember who you are. A cookie will normally contain the name of the internet domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. We use cookies to evaluate the general use of the Site. We also use cookies to identify who you are after you log in or register so that we can tailor your personal preferences for a more personalized experience. Cookies also insure that the appearance of the Site conforms to your Internet browser. You usually can configure your Internet browser to reject cookies. However, if you do so, you might not be able to access certain pages or use important functions on the Site. We reserve the right to introduce new passive tracking technologies and techniques related to the use of the Site. In general, we do not link your identity with information that we collect passively. However, in any situation where you log in with your username and password, any or all of the information that is passively collected about your activities on the Site may be linked with your identity, and therefore may become Personal Information about you.  
To learn more about cookies and other passive tracking technologies and how they may be used on your computer, please read the help information supplied with your Internet browser software.

### Active Information Collection

In general, when you visit the Site you remain anonymous, but on some pages, you need to provide Personal Information to register, enter a competition, contact us, and conduct other activities and transactions via the Site. The types of Personal Information collected at the Site may include any or all of the following, depending on your activities on the Site: name, address, e-mail address, phone number, fax number, website, organization (including the organization’s name, website, phone number, and address), username, password, language, photograph and other Personal Information that you actively provide to us via the Site.  
We also enable you to submit Personal Information about other people. For example, we request that you provide us with such information about individuals who you wish to nominate for a competition sponsored by Changemakers, or to use as references, or who may be interested in hearing about Changemakers. The following types of Personal Information may be collected about such persons: name, organization name, email address, phone number, city, and country.

### Use of Personal Information

We use and disclose Personal Information to provide information about our organization, our competitions, or other issues of interest.  
Except as provided herein, WE WILL NOT SELL ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION THAT YOU PROVIDE THROUGH THE SITE WITHOUT YOUR PRIOR WRITTEN CONSENT. We may use Personal Information that you provide to update you on our activities, let you know about new projects and competitions that we believe may be of interest to you, and contact you about the outcome of competitions. If you do not want to receive this information in the future, please contact us at [connect@changemakers.com](mailto:connect@changemakers.com "Linkification: mailto:connect@changemakers.com").  
From time to time, we may share certain Personal Information with other non-profits to enable them to share information that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to share Personal Information with these entities, please contact us at[ ](mailto:privacy@changemakers.net)[connect@changemakers.com](mailto:connect@changemakers.com) and we will take reasonable measures to avoid sharing such information in the future. Please note that these other parties are sometimes independent from Changemakers, and if your information has already been shared with such parties and you wish to stop all communications from such parties and/or stop any use of the shared information by such parties, you will need to address such issues with them directly.   
We may share Personal Information with our partners, affiliates, consultants, suppliers, and providers. We require that these entities keep your Personal Information confidential and only use your Personal Information to the extent necessary to perform their functions and not for any other purpose.   
We may disclose Personal Information in response to legal process or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, for example, in response to a court order, subpoena, or a law enforcement agency's request. We also reserve the right to disclose Personal Information to protect the security of the Site, and to protect ourselves and our partners, affiliates, consultants, suppliers, and providers against liability.    
In the event that Changemakers or a significant portion of Changemakers’ assets or business is sold, assigned, merged, or otherwise transferred, Changemakers may transfer your Personal Information as a part of the transaction. In the event such a transfer occurs, Changemakers will use reasonable efforts to keep your Personal Information subject to the same protection as it was prior to the transfer. In the event that your Personal Information becomes subject to a different privacy policy, Changemakers will use reasonable efforts to notify you of such change.   
The Site is not directed to children and Changemakers does not knowingly solicit information from any child under the age of 13.

### How You Can Access or Correct Your Information

If you are a registered user of the Site, you can access and correct certain Personal Information that we collect online and maintain by clicking on "sign in" and entering your username and password. If any errors in your Personal Information cannot be corrected by accessing your account or if you have other questions related to updating or changing your account information, please contact us using the contact information below. You may also contact us using the information below to ask us to remove your Personal Information from our records, electronic or otherwise.

### Use of Anonymous Information

The Site's web servers collect anonymous logs during user visits to the Site. This information is used to create aggregate statistics, for example, when the Site is accessed, the pages which refer visitors to the Site, the type of web browsers visitors use, and which pages of the Site are viewed. These statistics help us understand how the Site is used and provide us with valuable information for improving the Site in the future. From time to time, we may share such aggregate, non-personally identifiable statistical information with ­­advertisers and our partners, affiliates, consultants, suppliers, and providers. The type and amount of information we receive and store depends on how you use the Site. You can access most of our pages without telling us who you are and without revealing any Personal Information.

### Security

Changemakers tries very hard to protect our users' Personal Information. Though Changemakers strives to protect this information, no transmission of data is completely secure. Changemakers will not be liable under any circumstances for damages resulting from use of information collected from you or any other visitors to the Site. When you access your account information, we usually offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software receives encrypted information through the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) of your Internet browser which encrypts the Personal Information you input before it is sent to us and seeks to prevent anyone from reading it as the information travels from your computer to ours.  
You should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose Personal Information via competition entries, messages, forums, postings, or in other areas of the Site, that information, along with any substantive information disclosed in your communication, can be collected and correlated and used by third parties and may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of Changemakers.  Please do not post any Personal Information on the Site that you expect to keep private.

### Usernames and Passwords

It is your responsibility to safeguard any username or password that you have received in connection with the Site, and to notify us if you ever suspect that the security and confidentiality of such username or password has been compromised in any way. You are solely responsible for any use of the Site via your username and password.

### Links

Please note that third parties may also collect information about you, through cookies or other technologies, when you link to their websites through the Site. We do not monitor or control the information collection or privacy practices of these or any other third parties, and are not responsible for their practices or the content of their websites. If you are concerned about how third parties collect and use information, please review their privacy practices posted on their websites.

### Changes to Changemakers Privacy Policy

Our privacy practices, like the online medium itself, are subject to change. Changemakers may, in its sole discretion, change this Privacy Policy at any time to reflect changes in the way we collect and use Personal Information in the future. Please check this Privacy Policy frequently and particularly before you submit additional Personal Information via the Site. All revisions to this Privacy Policy will be posted on the Site via a link from the home page of the Site. Your continued use of the Site after changes in this Privacy Policy indicates your assent to such changes.

### International Users

Changemakers collects, processes, stores, discloses, and disposes of Personal Information that you submit to us in accordance with applicable United States law. Please note that the Personal Information you submit to the Site will be transferred to the United States to be processed by Changemakers in order to provide the Site and its services to you or for such other purposes as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If you are not a resident of the United States, you acknowledge and agree that we may collect and use your Personal Information, as discussed in this Privacy Policy, outside your resident jurisdiction. In addition, we may store such Personal Information in the United States, outside your resident jurisdiction. In particular, you are advised that the United States uses a sectoral model of privacy protection that relies on a mix of legislation, governmental regulation, and self-regulation. Please be aware that United States law may offer different levels of protection for Personal Information than may be available in your country.

### How to Contact Us

Your privacy is very important to us. Should you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please address them to:  
Changemakers  
1700 North Moore Street  
Suite 2000  
Arlington, VA 22209  
You may also send us an email at [connect@changemakers.com](mailto:privacy@changemakers.net).
